# **CAMILLE COCHENER**

# Data Scientist (+4 years of experience)

It's been 4 years I'm working in Data Science: 3 as professional experience in several major groups and startups and 1 through an intensive training in Big Data at Télécom Paris. Three words to define myself: passionate, efficient and eager to share.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **DATA SCIENTIST - COMPUTER VISION**

Lixo - Startup created at the end of 2019 - 5 employees Agoranov, Paris, France

Lixo develops quality control solutions for waste management

I was responsible of the AI module (a computer vision application).

- Implemented and trained object detection and segmentation models
- Experimented several sets of hyperparameters to reach best performance
- Optimized Deep Learning models on a microcomputer (TensorRT, NVIDIA Jetson)
- Wrote scientific documentation to apply for funding awards (Bourse French Tech Emergence, i-Lab)

Results: +50% improvement of the initial model, models deployed at the client's facility, +90K€ grant earned

Tools: Deep Learning, Data Engineering, Python, OpenCV, TensorFlow API, Keras, PyTorch, GCP, Linux, Git

**DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT** 

Consulting company: IT&M STATS (IT&M group)

Neuilly-sur-Seine, France

Jan 2017 - July 2019 (2,5 years)

**ESSILOR** 

July 2020 - Jan 2021

(6 months)

lixo

► ESSILOR INTERNATIONAL, R&D, Créteil, France (10 months, 10/2018 - 07/2019)

Led the 1st Data Science project related to the analysis of historical data in order to optimize the TimeToMarket of anti-reflective products.

- Worked with glass experts to understand business requirements
- Conducted process mapping and data inventory

• Explored and analyzed data using Dataiku DSS, AWS, SQL, Python and R (PCA, MFA, Machine Learning)

- Presented results to decision-makers (Head of R&D, head of development)
- Trained staff to data science methods and programming

Results: Delivered an analytical report, highlighting areas of improvement regarding the data strategy of the company

► L'ORÉAL R&I, Chevilly-Larue, France (1,5 year, 03/2017 - 09/2018)

Supported the Scientific Computing team for day-to-day data science projects.

l'ORÉAL

- Participated to kick-off meetings with Research & Innovation laboratories
- Cleansed, preprocessed and explored data with visualization, PCA, MFA and statistical tests
- Carried-out analysis and data modeling using Statistical and Machine Learning techniques (analysis of variance, linear regression, PLS, s-PLS, decision trees, Random Forests, clustering)
- Developed applications and R packages for routine analysis (GWidgets, RShiny)

Results: Released 2 applications, meant to automate the analysis and save time. +15 projects achieved.

► IT&M STATS' INTERNAL DIVISION, Neuilly-sur-Seine, France (2,5 year, 01/2017 – 07/2019)

Participated in fixed-price projects and R programming training.

- CHORUM mutual: Segmented customer portfolio and predicted appetence score (1 month)
- Clarins Laboratories: Analyzed the influence of instrumental parameters on pore size (1 month)
- Société Générale: Trained professional staff to R packages DPLYR & TIDYR (2 days)

Tools: Statistics, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, R, Python, SQL, Dataiku DSS, Spotfire

#### DATA SCIENTIST - INTERNSHIP FOR GRADUATE MASTER DEGREE

Clarins Laboratories

Pontoise, France

March 2016 - Sept 2016 (6 months)

2020

2020

2019 - 2020

TELECOM

三級 開始

Modeling the relationships between consumer perceptions and instrumental measurements of skin mechanical properties.

## **SUCCESS**

▶ AI & Data Science Challenge - Carrefour / I'X - 1st out of 26 teams

Designed a local Marketing Mix Modeling – analysis and prediction of the impact of marketing media on

▶ AI & Machine Learning Hackathon - QMI / Dauphine - 4<sup>th</sup> out of 26 teams

Predicted stock volatility among the S&P500 and Stoxx600 on performance announcement dates-24h

3 teammates - Python, XGBoost, Random Forests, Stacking, Hyperopt

sales (ROI) - 2 months - 6 teammates - GCP, Big Query, Python, CatBoost, Dash, Shap, MMM

▶ Winner of "Trophée Syntec" & Travel Award for a congress in Hô Chi Minh City 2016

## **EDUCATION**

### ▶ Post Master Degree in Big Data - Télécom Paris (IP Paris)

Achieved several Data Science and Data Engineering projects with Python, Spark and Java

- Predicted the number of bikes shared at a station with Spark
- Designed a resilient ETL for the analysis of GDELT database (Spark/Cassandra/AWS)
- Fusionned algorithm outputs for facial recognition (IDEMIA)
- Performed anomaly detection on helicopter accelerometer data (Challenge Airbus)
- Built a NLP model to classify toxic comments (Challenge Kaggle Jigsaw)
- ► Agronomic Engineer Master degree Statistics & Data Science (double degree) Agrocampus Ouest/Rennes II University, Rennes
- ▶ Preparatory Classes for the "Grandes Écoles" Lycée Chaptal, Paris

IP PARIS

2010 - 2013

2013 - 2016

Baking

Paris, France cochenercamille@yahoo.fr

O +33 6 71 46 78 07

11/05/1992 (28 yo)

Github: camillecochener LinkedIn: camillecochener Available: 02/2021

### **SKILLS**

Data exploration

Machine Learning & Deep Learning

R, Python, SQL Programming

Keras, TensorFlow API, PvTorch

Data Engineering

GCP. AWS

Visualization

Git. Linux, MacOS, Docker

Curiosity

Team player

Problem-solving

Rigor

Communication

## **LANGUAGES**

- French (Native)
- English (Fluent)

# **PERSONAL** DEVELOPMENT

#### **Coursera Certificates:**

- Deep Learning (CNN, Sequence Models) by deeplearning.ai
- Java Programming by Duke University
- Data Science Specialization by John Hopkins University

#### Meet-up:

- Speaker (Paris Data Ladies December 2020 edition on Computer Vision, 100 Data experts)
- Attendee (Paris Data Ladies, Data for Good)

# **HOBBIES**

## Sports:

- Horse riding
- Yoga
- Skiing
- Tennis

# Others:

- Traveling
- Team-based & strategy video games